A Guide to the Minutes of the Virginia Board of Funeral Directors and Embalmers, 2016-2021.
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Minutes of the Virginia Board of Funeral Directors and Embalmers,
2016-2021.
The Library of Virginia
53862
Virginia. Dept. of Health Professions.
1.05 cu. ft.
Administrative Information
Arranged chronologically.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions
Acquisition Information
Accession 53860 was transferred by the Dept. of Health Professions on 04/13/2023.
Historical Information
Regulation of the health professions began late in the nineteenth century. On January 31, 1884, the General Assembly passed an act creating the Board of Medical Examiners to certify physicians for practice in Virginia. Two years later, acts establishing the Board of Dental Examiners (now the Board of Dentistry) and the Board of Pharmacy were passed by the General Assembly on February 26 and March 3, 1886, respectively. The Board of Embalmers (now the Board of Funeral Directors and Embalmers) was created by an act passed on March 5, 1894, and the Board of Veterinary Examiners (now the Board of Veterinary Medicine) was established by an act passed on February 27, 1896. On May 1, 1903, the General Assembly created the Board of Graduate Nurses (now the State Board of Nursing), and on March 11, 1916, the Board of Optometry was established by legislative action.
The Dept. of Health Regulatory Boards was created by an act passed by the General Assembly on March 31, 1977, to provide administrative services to the health regulatory boards of the state. The boards continue to regulate their professions through the examination, licensing, and disciplining of the practitioners of health science. In 1986, the Dept. of Health Regulatory Boards became the Dept. of Health Professions. Its mission is to enhance the delivery of safe and competent health care by licensing qualified health care professionals, enforcing standards of practice, and providing information to both practitioners and consumers of health care services.
Scope and Content
Official minutes and related attachments documenting the meetings, activities, discussions and policy decisions and recommendations of the Virginia Board of Funeral Directors and Embalmers. Earlier volumes also include lists of licensure examination applicants. Also includes minutes for Committees and other groups (Legislative/Regulatory Committee, Special Conference Committee, Task Force on Cremation Laws and Regulations (2007), Task Force on the Inspection Process (2007)), as well as records related to informal conferences, telephone conferences, and formal hearings.
Contents List
- Minutes of the Virginia Board of Funeral Directors and Embalmers, 2016-2021.
  - Accession 53862 (2016-2021).
    - Board minutes, 2016 Jan 12. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Board minutes, 2016 Apr 19. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Formal administrative hearing, 2016 May 2. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Formal administrative hearing, 2016 June 3. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Informal fact finding conference, 2016 June 22. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Informal fact finding conference, 2016 Sept 29. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Board minutes, 2016 Oct 18. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Regulatory/Legislative Committee minutes, 2016 Dec 8. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Board minutes, 2017 Jan 10. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Formal administrative hearing and informal fact finding conference, 2017 Feb 10. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Informal fact finding conference, 2017 Mar 21. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Board Minutes and informal fact finding conference, 2017 Apr 18. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Internships minutes, 2017 July 13. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Informal fact finding conference, 2017 July 13. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Board minutes, 2017 July 18. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Formal administrative hearing and informal fact finding conference, 2017 July 18. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Informal fact finding confernce, 2017 Aug 24. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Examination Committee, 2017 Sept 5. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Internships minutes, 2017 Sept 22. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Board minutes, 2017 Oct 10. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Examination Committee minutes, 2017 Oct 10. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Executivie Director's Report (2016-2017), 2017 Oct. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Board minutes, 2018 Jan 16. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Formal administrative hearing and informal fact finding conference, 2018 Jan 16. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Internships minutes, 2018 Apr 13. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Informal fact finding conference, 2018 Apr 13. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Board minutes, 2018 Apr 17. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Formal administrative hearing, 2018 Apr 17. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Informal fact finding conference, 2018 June 13. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Internships minutes, 2018 July 10. (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Board minutes, 2018 July 12. (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Regulatory/Legislative Committee minutes, 2018 July 12. (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Informal fact finding conference, 2018 July 31. (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Board minutes, 2018 Oct 16. (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Informal fact finding conference, 2018 Oct 16. (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Formal administrative hearing, 2018 Oct 16. (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Informal fact finding conference, 2018 Oct 20. (Box 1, Folder 37)